<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel rdf:about="https://cambridge.org/core/rss/product/id1D0D890CD9100ADE91DAEB74509AB7C6"><title><![CDATA[Language and Cognition]]></title><description><![CDATA[&lt;i&gt;Language and Cognition&lt;/i&gt; is the official journal of the UK Cognitive Linguistics Association. It is a venue for the publication of high quality peer-reviewed research focusing on the interface between language and cognition. It is open to research from the full range of subject disciplines, theoretical backgrounds, and analytical frameworks that populate the language and cognitive sciences, on a wide range of topics. Research published in the journal uses an interdisciplinary, comparative, multi-methodological approach to advance understanding of language and cognition and their intersections. The editors especially encourage submissions that investigate the traditional areas of cognitive linguistics (e.g., conceptual semantics, linguistic categorization, iconicity, metaphor, linguistic relativity, embodied cognition, grammaticalization, construction-based grammar) using experimental, computational, and/or corpus-based methods. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The journal publishes original research articles, systematic review articles (meta-analyses), and book reviews. It does not publish technical reports, commentary articles, or position papers. Normally, book reviews and review articles are solicited by the editors. Please contact the Review Editor first if you would like to submit a book review; if you have an idea for a review article or a special issue of the journal, contact one of the General Editors with your proposal. Only original research articles may be submitted without invitation from one of the editors. Submitted articles should be no shorter than 8,000 words and no longer than 10,000 words, including references, footnotes and appendices. Submissions that significantly exceed the 10,000-word upper limit may be returned by editors without comment or review.]]></description><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/language-and-cognition/latest-issue</link><prism:publicationName>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationName><prism:issn>18669808</prism:issn><prism:eissn>18669859</prism:eissn><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core"/><dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press</dc:publisher><image rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico"></image><items><rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.17"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.18"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.22"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.25"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.3"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.19"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.20"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.21"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.24"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.1"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.2"/></rdf:Seq></items></channel><image  rdf:about="https://www.cambridge.org/core"><url>https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico</url><title>Cambridge Core</title><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core</link></image><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.17"><title><![CDATA[Discourse context modulates the effect of implicit causality on rementions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Certain verbs tend to elicit explanations about either their subject or their object. The tendency for one of the verb’s arguments to be rementioned in explanations is known as the implicit causality bias. In this paper we investigate the conditions underlying implicit causality remention biases by means of sentence and story completion studies. On one account of implicit causality, remention biases are the product of a combination of a particular lexico-semantic structure with a causal coherence relation. According to a competing account, the biases arise from a perceived lack of information in the discourse, and thus depend on knowledge about the world and the discourse context. To distinguish between the two accounts, it first needs to be established that information that potentially competes with implicit causality, such as relevant information from the discourse context, can reliably influence remention biases. We provide evidence that a violation of implicit assumptions underlying the standard use of implicit causality verbs leads to different inferences, and an alteration of the remention bias. We thereby lay the groundwork for future studies to distinguish between the two accounts.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.17?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.17</dc:identifier><dc:title>Discourse context modulates the effect of implicit causality on rementions</dc:title><prism:startingPage>561</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>594</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.17</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.17</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-10-02</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-10-02</dc:date><dc:creator>VAN DEN HOVEN, EMIEL</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERSTL, EVELYN C.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.18"><title><![CDATA[The verbatim access effect: implicature in experimental context]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Implicature interpretation is sensitive to many contextual factors. This experimental study investigates two:<ol><li><span class='abs-list-label'>(A)</span>instructions to think carefully about exactly what is said</li><li><span class='abs-list-label'>(B)</span>access to the verbatim form of what has been said</li></ol></p><p>Participants encountered (1) below, which can give rise to the contradictory relevance implicature in (2), as feedback during a decoy task:<ol><li><span class='abs-list-label'>(1)</span>I’m not suggesting that you’re responding too slowly, but it’s important to give the first response that comes to mind.</li><li><span class='abs-list-label'>(2)</span>(I am suggesting that) you’re responding too slowly.</li></ol></p><p>When participants were questioned post-task, (B) significantly reduced rates of agreement that the speaker of (1) had said (2), whether the verbatim form provided was written (Experiment 1) or audio (Experiment 2). (A) had no such effect. In Experiment 3, we added a final task for participants: to recall (1) verbatim. One-third had forgotten it, typically substituting the implicature (2). We argue that this memory loss can explain the lower implicature rates associated with verbatim access: verbatim access reminds forgetful participants of (1)’s compositional interpretation, and that interpretation is inconsistent with the implicature in (2). Consequently, verbatim access reduces the chances of endorsing (2), thus introducing an inherent literal meaning bias in interpreting previous conversation.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.18?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.18</dc:identifier><dc:title>The verbatim access effect: implicature in experimental context</dc:title><prism:startingPage>595</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>625</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.18</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.18</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-12-06</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-12-06</dc:date><dc:creator>SIEGEL, MUFFY</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZEHR, JÉRÉMY</dc:creator><dc:creator>BACOVCIN, HEZEKIAH AKIVA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHOFIELD, LYNNE STEUERLE</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHWARZ, FLORIAN</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.22"><title><![CDATA[When words burn – language processing differentially modulates pain perception in typical and chronic pain populations]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>How do we communicate our pain to others? The challenge of conveying such a highly individual experience in words is faced daily by many sufferers of chronic pain and their doctors. Moreover, such linguistic strategies are especially relevant in situations where no obvious reference to physical injuries or tissue damage can be made. Neurolinguistically, this question is directly linked to understanding the brain mechanisms behind the encoding, storage, and comprehension of word meanings. An influential view posits that comprehension involves mentally simulating sensorimotor experiences which words refer to. Here, we test the hypothesis that both pain word comprehension and first-hand experiences of pain rely on a common neural substrate, leading to a prediction that word processing should modulate the perception of noxious stimuli. We used a priming task and asked neurotypical and chronic pain participants to read sentences containing literal or metaphoric pain descriptors, and then rate the intensity of thermal pain stimuli. We found that pain language comprehension modulated participants’ ratings of pain intensity. Furthermore, this effect depended on linguistic context as well as individual pain history. We discuss our findings within the larger theoretical debate on the nature of semantic representations, and point to their potential relevance for clinical practice.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.22?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.22</dc:identifier><dc:title>When words burn – language processing differentially modulates pain perception in typical and chronic pain populations</dc:title><prism:startingPage>626</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>640</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.22</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.22</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-01-10</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-01-10</dc:date><dc:creator>VUKOVIC, NIKOLA</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARDO, FRANCESCA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHTYROV, YURY</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.25"><title><![CDATA[Gesture frequency is linked to story-telling style: evidence from bilinguals]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Individuals differ in how frequently they gesture. It is not clear whether gesture frequency is related to culture, since varied results have been reported. The purpose of this study was to test whether the frequency of representational gestures is linked with story-telling style. Previous research showed individual and cross-cultural differences in story-telling style, some preferring to tell a chronicle (how it happened) or an evaluative story (why it happened). We hypothesized that high gesture frequency might be strongly associated with using a chronicle style, since both rely on visuospatial imagery. Four groups of bilinguals, English as their second language (L2) participated. Their first language (L1) was one of: Mandarin, Hindi, French, or Spanish. Participants watched a cartoon and told the story, once in English, once in L1. The results showed group differences in the rate of gesture use: the Chinese and Hindi L1 participants gestured less frequently than the French and Spanish L1 participants. The participants from Asian cultures were more likely to tell an evaluative story and the Romance-language L1 participants a chronicle. We conclude that these culture/language groups differ in story-telling style. A chronicle style is associated with more gesture production than an evaluative style.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.25?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.25</dc:identifier><dc:title>Gesture frequency is linked to story-telling style: evidence from bilinguals</dc:title><prism:startingPage>641</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>664</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.25</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.25</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-02-15</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-02-15</dc:date><dc:creator>NICOLADIS, ELENA</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGPAL, JAYA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARENTETTE, PAULA</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAUER, BRANDON</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.3"><title><![CDATA[Figure and Ground in spatial language: evidence from German and Korean]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>We investigate how German and Korean speakers describe everyday spatial/motion events, such as putting a cup on the table. In these motion events, the <span class='sc'>moving object</span> (e.g., cup) and the <span class='sc'>non-moving reference object</span> (e.g., table) take on the roles of Figure and Ground, respectively. Figure(F) and Ground(G) thus have distinct perceptual properties and assume conceptually asymmetric roles (entity moving along a trajectory vs. stationary reference frame). We examine the degrees to which speakers distinguish between F and G semantically (spatial/Path terms, e.g., <span class='italic'>on</span>, <span class='italic'>in</span>) and syntactically (grammatical roles, e.g., subject, object). Participants described events involving two objects that switched their F-G roles (<span class='italic'>put cup</span>(F) <span class='italic'>on board</span>(G) and <span class='italic'>put board</span>(F) <span class='italic'>under cup</span>(G)). German speakers use distinct Path terms (e.g., <span class='italic'>auf</span>, <span class='italic'>in</span>) for differential F-G relations, thus encoding the F-G asymmetry. In contrast, Korean speakers use the same terms (e.g., <span class='italic'>kkita</span> ‘fit.tightly’) and the same syntactic constructions regardless of switches in F-G roles. These cross-linguistic differences are evident for Non-typical events (<span class='italic'>Put board</span>(F) <span class='italic'>under cup</span>(G)), showing that the encoding of the asymmetry interacts with speakers’ everyday experiences of motion events. We argue that the differences reflect the interactions between the Path lexicon and spatial syntax, and language-specific viewpoints of the F-G relation.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.3?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2019.3</dc:identifier><dc:title>Figure and Ground in spatial language: evidence from German and Korean</dc:title><prism:startingPage>665</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>700</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2019.3</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.3</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-03-07</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-03-07</dc:date><dc:creator>CHOI, SOONJA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOLLER, FLORIAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>HONG, UPYONG</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANSORGE, ULRICH</dc:creator><dc:creator>YUN, HONGOAK</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.19"><title><![CDATA[Pius ten Hacken (Ed.), The Semantics of Compounding. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2016. Pp. 264. ISBN 978-1-107-09970-8]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.19?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.19</dc:identifier><dc:title>Pius ten Hacken (Ed.), The Semantics of Compounding. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2016. Pp. 264. ISBN 978-1-107-09970-8</dc:title><prism:startingPage>701</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>706</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.19</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.19</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-12-06</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-12-06</dc:date><dc:creator>SCHAEFER, MARTIN</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.20"><title><![CDATA[Prakash Mondal, Language and Cognitive Structures of Emotion. Palgrave Macmillan, 2016. Pp. xvii, 182. ISBN 978-33-193-3689-3.]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.20?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.20</dc:identifier><dc:title>Prakash Mondal, Language and Cognitive Structures of Emotion. Palgrave Macmillan, 2016. Pp. xvii, 182. ISBN 978-33-193-3689-3.</dc:title><prism:startingPage>706</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>710</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.20</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.20</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-12-06</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-12-06</dc:date><dc:creator>BEHME, CHRISTINA</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.21"><title><![CDATA[Letitia R. Naigles (Ed.), Innovative Investigations of Language in Autism Spectrum Disorder. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association / Berlin: Walter de Gruyter, 2017. Pp. 253. ISBN 978-311-040-978-9 (Hb), 311-040-978-X (E-Book)]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.21?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.21</dc:identifier><dc:title>Letitia R. Naigles (Ed.), Innovative Investigations of Language in Autism Spectrum Disorder. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association / Berlin: Walter de Gruyter, 2017. Pp. 253. ISBN 978-311-040-978-9 (Hb), 311-040-978-X (E-Book)</dc:title><prism:startingPage>711</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>720</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.21</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.21</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-12-18</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-12-18</dc:date><dc:creator>XIE, FAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PASCUAL, ESTHER</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.24"><title><![CDATA[Paul Chilton and Monika Kopytowska (Eds.), Religion, Language, and the Human Mind. New York: Oxford University Press, 2018. Pp. Iii+483. ISBN 978-0-19-063664-7 (Hb)]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.24?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2018.24</dc:identifier><dc:title>Paul Chilton and Monika Kopytowska (Eds.), Religion, Language, and the Human Mind. New York: Oxford University Press, 2018. Pp. Iii+483. ISBN 978-0-19-063664-7 (Hb)</dc:title><prism:startingPage>720</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>727</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2018.24</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2018.24</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-01-25</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-01-25</dc:date><dc:creator>MCDONOUGH, TERRY</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.1"><title><![CDATA[LCO volume 10 issue 4 Cover and Front matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.1?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2019.1</dc:identifier><dc:title>LCO volume 10 issue 4 Cover and Front matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>2</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2019.1</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.1</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-03-07</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-03-07</dc:date></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.2"><title><![CDATA[LCO volume 10 issue 4 Cover and Back matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.2?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/langcog.2019.2</dc:identifier><dc:title>LCO volume 10 issue 4 Cover and Back matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>3</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/langcog.2019.2</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/langcog.2019.2</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-03-07</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-03-07</dc:date></item></rdf:RDF>