<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel rdf:about="https://cambridge.org/core/rss/product/id89E81FB21B749A8242E89C9FF383859A"><title><![CDATA[Studies in Second Language Acquisition]]></title><description><![CDATA[&lt;i&gt;Studies in Second Language Acquisition&lt;/i&gt; is a refereed journal of international scope devoted to the scientific discussion of acquisition or use of non-native and heritage languages. Each volume (four issues) contains research articles of either a quantitative or qualitative nature in addition to essays on current theoretical matters. Other rubrics include shorter articles such as Replication Studies, Critical Commentaries, and Research Reports. ]]></description><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/studies-in-second-language-acquisition/latest-issue</link><prism:publicationName>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationName><prism:issn>02722631</prism:issn><prism:eissn>14701545</prism:eissn><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core"/><dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press</dc:publisher><image rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico"></image><items><rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311700033X"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000013"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000165"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000049"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000037"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000141"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000116"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000177"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000025"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263117000249"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000293"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311800030X"/></rdf:Seq></items></channel><image  rdf:about="https://www.cambridge.org/core"><url>https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico</url><title>Cambridge Core</title><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core</link></image><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311700033X"><title><![CDATA[MOTIVATION AS QUALITY]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>The study examined the predictions of regulatory fit theory (Higgins, 2000) in relation to task-based incidental vocabulary learning. A total of 189 English as a second language learners completed a vocabulary pretest, a regulatory focus questionnaire, an integrated reading/writing task, and finally an unannounced vocabulary posttest. The participants were randomly assigned to two task conditions. In the gain condition, they started the task with zero points and had to gain 75 points to enter a drawing to win one of three $100 gift cards; in the loss condition, they started with 100 points and had to avoid losing more than 25 points. Multiple regression results partly supported the regulatory fit predictions. Prevention individuals learned significantly more vocabulary items in the loss condition than in the gain condition; but promotion individuals did not learn significantly more vocabulary items in the gain condition than in the loss condition. Theoretical and pedagogical implications, and future research directions are discussed.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311700033X?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S027226311700033X</dc:identifier><dc:title>MOTIVATION AS QUALITY</dc:title><prism:startingPage>707</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>730</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S027226311700033X</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311700033X</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-01-29</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-01-29</dc:date><dc:creator>Papi, Mostafa</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000013"><title><![CDATA[QUANTIFICATIONAL CUES MODULATE THE PROCESSING OF ENGLISH SUBJECT-VERB AGREEMENT BY NATIVE CHINESE SPEAKERS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Numerous studies have demonstrated that native Mandarin speakers have pervasive difficulties processing L2 English agreement morphology. However, less is known about the lexical and morphological cues that may modulate Mandarin speakers’ sensitivity to English number agreement. To investigate this, we examined subject-verb agreement processing in English by L1 Mandarin participants using event-related brain potentials (ERPs) and focused on the use of quantificational cues to noun number and their interaction with agreement morphology on the verb. Previous work in English monolinguals has shown that agreement violations elicited larger P600s when preceded by a plurally quantified subject noun phrase (NP) compared to an unquantified NP. In the present study, Mandarin speakers were tested on the same quantified and unquantified sentences (e.g., <span class='italic'>Most/The cookies <span class='underline'>taste/*tastes</span>…</span>) as in the prior work. Like the L1 English speakers, ERPs time-locked to the verb showed a reliable P600 in response to agreement violations. However, the P600 in Mandarin speakers was larger for ungrammatical verbs with <span class='italic'>un</span>quantified subjects, a contrast with English monolinguals. First, these results demonstrate that L2 agreement violations can elicit qualitatively similar neural responses in L1 Mandarin speakers as in English monolinguals (P600 effects), a finding that is to our knowledge novel. Second, quantification modulated the P600 in the L2 speakers in a qualitatively different way than in natives. Overall, these findings suggest stronger reliance on lexical versus morphological cues to number in Mandarin speakers, and that this impacts anticipation of subsequent grammatical features.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000013?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000013</dc:identifier><dc:title>QUANTIFICATIONAL CUES MODULATE THE PROCESSING OF ENGLISH SUBJECT-VERB AGREEMENT BY NATIVE CHINESE SPEAKERS</dc:title><prism:startingPage>731</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>754</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000013</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000013</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-03-22</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-03-22</dc:date><dc:creator>Armstrong, Andrew</dc:creator><dc:creator>Bulkes, Nyssa</dc:creator><dc:creator>Tanner, Darren</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000165"><title><![CDATA[THE EFFECTS OF READING ACTIVITY CHARACTERISTICS ON L2 READING PROCESSES AND NOTICING OF GLOSSED CONSTRUCTIONS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This study examined the extent to which manipulating the characteristics of second language reading activities affects the reading process and noticing of glossed linguistic constructions. Thirty-eight Korean learners of English read two texts under conditions that required more or less careful reading. For the condition intended to promote more careful reading, each paragraph of the texts was divided into three or four subparts. For the condition expected to elicit less careful reading, each paragraph was split into two sections. While reading the texts, the participants’ eye movements were recorded. Eleven students were further invited to participate in stimulated recall protocols. The target constructions were English unaccusative verbs and 10 pseudowords, which were glossed with Korean translations. The eye movement and stimulated recall data indicated that, as predicted, the participants processed the texts more carefully and attended to the target verbs more closely when paragraphs were divided into more subparts.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000165?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000165</dc:identifier><dc:title>THE EFFECTS OF READING ACTIVITY CHARACTERISTICS ON L2 READING PROCESSES AND NOTICING OF GLOSSED CONSTRUCTIONS</dc:title><prism:startingPage>755</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>780</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000165</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000165</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-10-16</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-10-16</dc:date><dc:creator>Jung, Jookyoung</dc:creator><dc:creator>Révész, Andrea</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000049"><title><![CDATA[SUBJECT POSITION AND INFORMATION STRUCTURE IN L2 SPANISH]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This study investigates the acquisition of the constraints regulating subject position in the L2 Spanish spoken by English native speakers and provides a representational account following the premises of the Multiple Grammars (MG) model. The acceptability of preverbal and postverbal subjects is compared considering different discursive contexts (i.e., broad focus, Verbal Phase [VP] focus, and subject focus). Three groups (i.e., native speakers, intermediate learners, and advanced learners), with 28 subjects each, took part in the study. Findings show that advanced speakers behave in a more nativelike manner than intermediate learners. Learners, nonetheless, are not capable of blocking the acceptability of preverbal subjects in those contexts in which native speakers disfavor them and show high productivity levels of underspecified L2 rules that lead them to accept postverbal subjects in infelicitous contexts (e.g., VP focus). These results are consistent with MG, the representation model proposed by Amaral and Roeper (2014), because an acquisition path can be described using simple rules with lexical or pragmatic restrictions, which may be targetlike. Optionality can be explained considering that L1 and L2 rules coexist and are never deleted, simply assigned different productivity levels or blocked.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000049?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000049</dc:identifier><dc:title>SUBJECT POSITION AND INFORMATION STRUCTURE IN L2 SPANISH</dc:title><prism:startingPage>781</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>803</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000049</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000049</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-16</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-16</dc:date><dc:creator>Sánchez Alvarado, Covadonga</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000037"><title><![CDATA[ACADEMIC BUOYANCY]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This article reports the first attempt to test the relevance of buoyancy—the capacity to overcome the setbacks, challenges, and pressures that are part of the ordinary course of school life—for instructed second language (L2) learning. Questionnaire data from 787 college-level L2 learners in South Korea assessed their academic buoyancy and a set of six hypothesized predictors. A two-step cluster analysis of the data identified five prominent L2 learner archetypes, providing evidence for the existence of L2 domain-specific buoyancy profiles. Using structural equation modeling, we examined links among the six predictor variables, buoyancy, and L2 achievement and grade point average (GPA). The results showed that buoyancy significantly predicted both L2 achievement and GPA and mediated the effect of the predictors on these two outcome variables. Buoyancy, thus, captures a dimension of L2 motivation that is conceptually and empirically distinct from existing constructs, and represents an essential yet underexplored capacity for success in language learning.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000037?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000037</dc:identifier><dc:title>ACADEMIC BUOYANCY</dc:title><prism:startingPage>805</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>830</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000037</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000037</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-16</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-16</dc:date><dc:creator>Yun, Saerom</dc:creator><dc:creator>Hiver, Phil</dc:creator><dc:creator>Al-Hoorie, Ali H.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000141"><title><![CDATA[STATISTICAL SENSITIVITY, COGNITIVE APTITUDES, AND PROCESSING OF COLLOCATIONS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Frequency and contingency (i.e., co-occurrence probability of words in multiword sequences [MWS]) are two driving forces of language acquisition and processing. Previous research has demonstrated that L1 and advanced L2 speakers are sensitive to phrasal frequency and contingency when processing larger-than-word units. However, it remains unclear whether such statistical sensitivity is robust across tasks and among subcategories of MWS. In addition, little is known about whether cognitive aptitudes can moderate such sensitivity. This study examined L1 and advanced L2 speakers’ statistical sensitivity to phrasal frequency and contingency as well as cognitive aptitudes’ moderating effects on such sensitivity when processing English adjective-noun collocations. Participants performed a phrasal acceptability judgment task (PJT). Meanwhile, their aptitude profiles were measured by six aptitude tests, which loaded separately onto implicit language aptitude, explicit language aptitude, and working memory capacity. Linear mixed-effects modeling revealed that both L1 and L2 English speakers were sensitive to phrasal frequency and contingency of collocations, although L2 speakers’ sensitivity was much stronger than that of L1 speakers. None of the aptitudes was found to moderate language users’ statistical sensitivity to either collocation frequency or contingency. Interestingly, disassociation patterns between the PJT performance and the involvement of implicit or explicit language aptitude among the L1 and L2 speakers were found. It was concluded that L1 and L2 speakers differed in terms of the way they processed the collocations, as well as the nature of their collocational knowledge.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000141?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000141</dc:identifier><dc:title>STATISTICAL SENSITIVITY, COGNITIVE APTITUDES, AND PROCESSING OF COLLOCATIONS</dc:title><prism:startingPage>831</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>856</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000141</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000141</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-07-24</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-07-24</dc:date><dc:creator>Yi, Wei</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000116"><title><![CDATA[L2 DEVELOPMENT OF PERCEPTUAL CATEGORIZATION OF DIALECTAL SOUNDS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>The present study examined second language (L2) development in the perceptual identification of a dialectal sound of the target language, through an investigation of the role of individual learner experiences in L2 phonological development. A total of 213 English-speaking learners of Spanish across five levels of study and with varying dialect contact experiences completed an identification task, which tested perceptual categorization of Spanish dialectal aspirated-s (e.g., <span class='italic'>siesta</span> [ˈsi̯eh-ta]). In accordance with postulates of L2 speech perception models (PAM-L2, SLM, L2LP), findings revealed influence of the first language phonology on categorization at early levels shifting toward nativelike, dialect-specific categorizations of aspirated-s for more experienced learners. Dialect contact factors of prior study abroad location, native speaker social contacts, and metalinguistic training were found to be predictors of the dialectal perceptual targets toward which the L2 learners developed—for those learners past intermediate-level language courses—highlighting how individual experiences shape L2 perceptual abilities.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000116?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000116</dc:identifier><dc:title>L2 DEVELOPMENT OF PERCEPTUAL CATEGORIZATION OF DIALECTAL SOUNDS</dc:title><prism:startingPage>857</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>882</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000116</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000116</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-06-26</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-06-26</dc:date><dc:creator>Schmidt, Lauren B.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000177"><title><![CDATA[THE EFFECT OF GLOSS TYPE ON LEARNERS’ INTAKE OF NEW WORDS DURING READING]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>A reading experiment combining online and offline data evaluates the effect on second language learners’ reading behaviors and lexical uptake of three gloss types designed to clarify word meaning. These are (a) textual definition, (b) textual definition accompanied by picture, and (c) picture only. We recorded eye movements while intermediate learners of English read a story presented on-screen and containing six glossed pseudowords repeated three times each. Cumulative fixation counts and time spent on the pseudowords predicted posttest performance for form recall and meaning recognition, confirming findings of previous eye-tracking studies of vocabulary acquisition from reading. However, the total visual attention given to pseudowords and glosses was smallest in the condition with picture-only glosses, and yet this condition promoted best retention of word meaning. This suggests that gloss types differentially influence learners’ processing of novel words in ways that may elude the quantitative measures of attention captured by eye-tracking.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000177?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000177</dc:identifier><dc:title>THE EFFECT OF GLOSS TYPE ON LEARNERS’ INTAKE OF NEW WORDS DURING READING</dc:title><prism:startingPage>883</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>906</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000177</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000177</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-08-13</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-08-13</dc:date><dc:creator>Warren, Paul</dc:creator><dc:creator>Boers, Frank</dc:creator><dc:creator>Grimshaw, Gina</dc:creator><dc:creator>Siyanova-Chanturia, Anna</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000025"><title><![CDATA[THE PRODUCTION OF SUBJECT-VERB AGREEMENT AMONG SWEDISH AND CHINESE SECOND LANGUAGE SPEAKERS OF ENGLISH]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This study uses a sentence completion task with Swedish and Chinese L2 English speakers to investigate how L1 morphosyntax and L2 proficiency influence L2 English subject-verb agreement production. Chinese has limited nominal and verbal number morphology, while Swedish has robust noun phrase (NP) morphology but does not number-mark verbs. Results showed that like L1 English speakers, both L2 groups used grammatical and conceptual number to produce subject-verb agreement. However, only L1 Chinese speakers—and less-proficient speakers in both L2 groups—were similarly influenced by grammatical and conceptual number when producing the subject NP. These findings demonstrate how L2 proficiency, perhaps combined with cross-linguistic differences, influence L2 production and underscore that encoding of noun and verb number are not independent.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000025?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000025</dc:identifier><dc:title>THE PRODUCTION OF SUBJECT-VERB AGREEMENT AMONG SWEDISH AND CHINESE SECOND LANGUAGE SPEAKERS OF ENGLISH</dc:title><prism:startingPage>907</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>921</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000025</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000025</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-06</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-06</dc:date><dc:creator>Jackson, Carrie N.</dc:creator><dc:creator>Mormer, Elizabeth</dc:creator><dc:creator>Brehm, Laurel</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263117000249"><title><![CDATA[THE ROLE OF PROCEDURAL LEARNING ABILITY IN AUTOMATIZATION OF L2 MORPHOLOGY UNDER DIFFERENT LEARNING SCHEDULES]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This paper reports on the reanalysis of Suzuki’s (2017) experiment and investigated the extent to which learning schedules influence automatization of second language (L2) morphology. Sixty participants were separated into two groups, which studied morphological rules for oral production under short-spacing (3.3-day intervals) and long-spacing learning conditions (7-day intervals). Their oral production test performance resulted in two measures of automatization: reaction time (RT) as an index of speedup and coefficient of variance (CV) as an index of stability/restructuring. The results showed that, while RT of both groups declined significantly after the training, the 3.3-day group exhibited greater propensity for restructuring than the 7-day group. Furthermore, procedural learning ability measured by the Tower of London task was significantly associated with RT, but not with CV, in the 3.3-day group only. These findings suggest that learning schedules and procedural learning ability influence different stages of automatization of L2 morphological learning.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263117000249?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263117000249</dc:identifier><dc:title>THE ROLE OF PROCEDURAL LEARNING ABILITY IN AUTOMATIZATION OF L2 MORPHOLOGY UNDER DIFFERENT LEARNING SCHEDULES</dc:title><prism:startingPage>923</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>937</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263117000249</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263117000249</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2017-08-10</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2017-08-10</dc:date><dc:creator>Suzuki, Yuichi</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000293"><title><![CDATA[SLA volume 40 issue 4 Cover and Front matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000293?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S0272263118000293</dc:identifier><dc:title>SLA volume 40 issue 4 Cover and Front matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>3</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S0272263118000293</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0272263118000293</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-11-29</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-11-29</dc:date></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311800030X"><title><![CDATA[SLA volume 40 issue 4 Cover and Back matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311800030X?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S027226311800030X</dc:identifier><dc:title>SLA volume 40 issue 4 Cover and Back matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>12</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S027226311800030X</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S027226311800030X</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-11-29</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-11-29</dc:date></item></rdf:RDF>