<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rdf:RDF xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:prism="http://prismstandard.org/namespaces/basic/2.0/"><channel rdf:about="https://cambridge.org/core/rss/product/idA21F66F2B26B14B043C6EEDBBE269DF7"><title><![CDATA[Bilingualism: Language and Cognition]]></title><description><![CDATA[&lt;I&gt;Bilingualism: Language and Cognition&lt;/I&gt; is an international peer-reviewed journal focusing on bilingualism from a linguistic, psycholinguistic, and neuroscientific perspective. The aims of the journal are to promote research on the bilingual and multilingual person and to encourage debate in the field. Areas covered include: bilingual language competence, bilingual language processing, bilingual language acquisition in children and adults, bimodal bilingualism, neurolinguistics of bilingualism in normal and brain-damaged individuals, computational modelling of bilingual language competence and performance, and the study of cognitive functions in bilinguals. BLC carries articles and research notes on all aspects of the bilingual person, including articles presenting research methods and research tools pertinent to the field of bilingualism.]]></description><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/bilingualism:-language-and-cognition/latest-issue</link><prism:publicationName>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationName><prism:issn>13667289</prism:issn><prism:eissn>14691841</prism:eissn><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core"/><dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press</dc:publisher><image rdf:resource="https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico"></image><items><rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000627"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000670"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800038X"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000712"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000748"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000366"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000378"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891700075X"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000299"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000044"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000682"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000640"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918001128"/><rdf:li rdf:resource="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800113X"/></rdf:Seq></items></channel><image  rdf:about="https://www.cambridge.org/core"><url>https://www.cambridge.org/core/cambridge-core/public/images/favicon.ico</url><title>Cambridge Core</title><link>https://www.cambridge.org/core</link></image><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000627"><title><![CDATA[Crosslinguistic interplay between semantics and phonology in late bilinguals: neurophysiological evidence]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>We investigated effects of crosslinguistic phonological and semantic similarity on the bilingual lexicon of late unbalanced bilinguals. Our masked priming paradigm used L1 (Russian) words as masked primes and L2 (English) words as targets. The primes and the targets either overlapped – phonologically, semantically, both phonologically and semantically – or did not overlap. Participants maintained the targets in memory and matched them against occasionally presented catch stimuli. N170 and N400 components of the word-elicited high-density ERPs were identified and analysed in signal and source space. Crosslinguistic semantic similarity shortened the reaction times. The semantics-related N400 amplitude difference correlated with individual L2 proficiency, while phonological similarity suppressed the N400 amplitude in the semantically unrelated condition. ERP source analysis suggests that these ERP dynamics are underpinned by cortical generators in the left IFG and the temporal pole. We conclude that the semantic and phonological interplay between L1 and L2 suggest an integrated bilingual lexicon.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000627?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000627</dc:identifier><dc:title>Crosslinguistic interplay between semantics and phonology in late bilinguals: neurophysiological evidence</dc:title><prism:startingPage>209</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>227</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000627</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000627</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-05-16</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-05-16</dc:date><dc:creator>NOVITSKIY, NIKOLAY</dc:creator><dc:creator>MYACHYKOV, ANDRIY</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHTYROV, YURY</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000670"><title><![CDATA[Conflict monitoring and detection in the bilingual brain]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Bilinguals sometimes outperform monolinguals on tasks involving cognitive control – the regulation of mental activity when confronted with information-processing conflict – perhaps stemming from experience monitoring for and resolving conflict between languages. We test the hypothesis that bilingualism affects moment-to-moment cognitive-control recruitment by examining how trial history influences bilinguals’ and monolinguals’ behavioral performance and associated neural activity on a Stroop task. We assessed dynamic effects of preceding trial conflict on current trial performance to separate the ability to proactively detect conflict (performance on new instances of conflict) from the ability to reactively recruit cognitive control (performance on trials following conflict). Across two experiments, monolinguals’ – but not bilinguals’ – accuracy decreased after non-conflict trials, i.e., when detecting initial conflicts. Bilinguals exhibited greater conflict-detection activity in ventrolateral prefrontal cortex (vlPFC/insula; BA 47) within a language-switching network, suggesting that they may monitor for information-conflict more proactively than monolinguals by recruiting brain regions involved in switching languages.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000670?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728917000670</dc:identifier><dc:title>Conflict monitoring and detection in the bilingual brain</dc:title><prism:startingPage>228</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>252</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728917000670</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000670</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2017-12-26</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2017-12-26</dc:date><dc:creator>TEUBNER-RHODES, SUSAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOLGER, DONALD J.</dc:creator><dc:creator>NOVICK, JARED M.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800038X"><title><![CDATA[Electrophysiological correlates of categorical perception of lexical tones by English learners of Mandarin Chinese: an ERP study]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This study examines brain responses to boundary effects with respect to Mandarin lexical <span class='italic'>tone</span> continua for three groups of adult listeners: (1) native English speakers who took advanced Mandarin courses; (2) naïve English speakers; and (3) native Mandarin speakers. A cross-boundary tone pair and a within-category tone pair derived from tonal contrasts <span class='italic'>(Mandarin Tone</span> 1/Tone 4; <span class='italic'>Tone</span> 2/Tone 3) with equal physical/acoustical distance were used in an auditory oddball paradigm. For native Mandarin speakers, the cross-category deviant elicited a larger MMN over left hemisphere sensors and larger P300 responses over both hemispheres relative to within-category deviants, suggesting categorical perception of tones at both pre-attentive and attentional stages of processing. In contrast, native English speakers and Mandarin learners did not demonstrate categorical effects. However, learners of Mandarin showed larger P300 responses than the other two groups, suggesting heightened sensitivity to tones and possibly greater attentional resource allocation to tone identification.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800038X?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S136672891800038X</dc:identifier><dc:title>Electrophysiological correlates of categorical perception of lexical tones by English learners of Mandarin Chinese: an ERP study</dc:title><prism:startingPage>253</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>265</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S136672891800038X</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800038X</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-06</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-06</dc:date><dc:creator>SHEN, GUANNAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>FROUD, KAREN</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000712"><title><![CDATA[The effect of task complexity on linguistic and non-linguistic control mechanisms in bilingual aphasia]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>In this study we examined linguistic and non-linguistic control mechanisms in 20 Spanish–English neurologically healthy bilingual adults and 13 Spanish–English bilingual adults with aphasia. Participants completed two linguistic and two non-linguistic control tasks accounting for low and high complexity. Healthy bilingual results were indicative of domain general cognitive control, whereas patient results were indicative of domain specific cognitive control. The magnitude of conflict required to complete the tasks was also examined. Healthy bilinguals exhibited significant amounts of conflict on all tasks and linguistic and non-linguistic conflict ratios were correlated; whereas patient results revealed significant conflict only on non-linguistic tasks and those conflict ratios were not correlated with linguistic conflict ratios, indicating a dissociation between how patients are controlling information in these two domains. Finally, a relationship between language impairment and language control was identified and brain damage was associated with linguistic and non-linguistic task performance.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000712?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728917000712</dc:identifier><dc:title>The effect of task complexity on linguistic and non-linguistic control mechanisms in bilingual aphasia</dc:title><prism:startingPage>266</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>284</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728917000712</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000712</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-01-19</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-01-19</dc:date><dc:creator>GRAY, TERESA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIRAN, SWATHI</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000748"><title><![CDATA[Revisiting the Revised Hierarchical Model: Evidence for concept mediation in backward translation]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>A claim fundamental to the revised hierarchical model (Kroll & Stewart, 1994) was that concepts did not mediate backward translation, based on their findings of a category interference effect in forward translation in relatively fluent bilinguals but no category effect in backward translation. This study hypothesized that there was a category facilitation effect in L2-to-concept, which counterbalanced the category interference effect in concept-to-L1, resulting in an overall L2-to-L1 null category effect.</p><p>In a novel English word-pair semantic comparison task, participants were presented with a sequence of English word-pairs, and judged which word's real-world referent was bigger in size. Results found a significant category facilitation effect in both L2-to-concept for young Chinese adults and L1-to-concept for young English adults when increasing the number of trials. The findings help explain why Kroll and Stewart's finding of an overall L2-to-L1 null category effect cannot be evidence against concept mediation in backward translation.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000748?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728917000748</dc:identifier><dc:title>Revisiting the Revised Hierarchical Model: Evidence for concept mediation in backward translation</dc:title><prism:startingPage>285</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>299</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728917000748</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000748</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-02-23</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-02-23</dc:date><dc:creator>WU, ZHAOHONG</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUFFS, ALAN</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000366"><title><![CDATA[The influence of proficiency and language combination on bilingual lexical access]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>The present study examines the influence of language proficiency and language combination on bilingual lexical access using category fluency in 109 healthy speakers. Participants completed a category fluency task in each of their languages in three main categories (<span class='italic'>animals, clothing</span>, and <span class='italic'>food</span>), each with two subcategories, as well as a language use questionnaire assessing their proficiency. Five language combinations were examined (Hindi–English, Kannada–English, Mandarin–English, Spanish–English, and Turkish–English). Multivariate analyses of variance revealed that the average number of correct items named in the category fluency task across the three main categories varied across the different groups only in English and not the other language. Further, results showed that language exposure composite (extracted from the questionnaire using a principal component analysis) significantly affected the average number of items named across the three main categories. Overall, these results demonstrate the effects of particular language combinations on bilingual lexical access and provide important insights into the role of proficiency on access.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000366?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000366</dc:identifier><dc:title>The influence of proficiency and language combination on bilingual lexical access</dc:title><prism:startingPage>300</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>330</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000366</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000366</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-05-07</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-05-07</dc:date><dc:creator>KASTENBAUM, JESSICA G.</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEDORE, LISA M.</dc:creator><dc:creator>PEÑA, ELIZABETH D.</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENG, LI</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAVIS, ILKNUR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEBASTIAN-VAYTADDEN, RAJANI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RANGAMANI, GRAMA</dc:creator><dc:creator>VALLILA-ROHTER, SOFIA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIRAN, SWATHI</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000378"><title><![CDATA[Bilingual memory, to the extreme: Lexical processing in simultaneous interpreters]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>This study assessed whether bilingual memory is susceptible to the extreme processing demands of professional simultaneous interpreters (PSIs). Seventeen PSIs and 17 non-interpreter bilinguals completed word production, lexical retrieval, and verbal fluency tasks. PSIs exhibited enhanced fluency in their two languages, and they were faster to translate words in both directions. However, no significant differences emerged in picture naming or word reading. This suggests that lexical enhancements in PSIs are confined to their specifically trained abilities (vocabulary search, interlingual reformulation), with no concomitant changes in other word-processing mechanisms. Importantly, these differences seem to reflect specifically linguistic effects, as both samples were matched for relevant executive skills. Moreover, only word translation performance correlated with the PSIs’ years of interpreting experience. Therefore, despite their tight cooperation, different subcomponents within bilingual memory seem characterized by independent, usage-driven flexibility.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000378?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000378</dc:identifier><dc:title>Bilingual memory, to the extreme: Lexical processing in simultaneous interpreters</dc:title><prism:startingPage>331</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>348</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000378</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000378</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-16</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-16</dc:date><dc:creator>SANTILLI, MICAELA</dc:creator><dc:creator>VILAS, MARTINA G.</dc:creator><dc:creator>MIKULAN, EZEQUIEL</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARTORELL CARO, MIGUEL</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUÑOZ, EDINSON</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEDEÑO, LUCAS</dc:creator><dc:creator>IBÁÑEZ, AGUSTÍN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARCÍA, ADOLFO M.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891700075X"><title><![CDATA[Language and literacy skills of home and international university students: How different are they, and does it matter?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Although international students experience lower attainment at university than home students (Morrison et al., <a href='#ref041'>2005</a>), reasons are poorly understood. Some question the role of language proficiency as international students come with required language qualifications. This study investigated language and literacy of international students who successfully met language entry requirements and those of home students, matched on non-verbal cognition, studying in their native language. In a sample of 63 Chinese and 64 British students at a UK university, large and significant group differences were found at entry and eight months later. Furthermore, language and literacy indicators explained 51% of variance in the Chinese group's grades, without predicting the home students’ achievement. Thus language proficiency appears predictive of academic outcomes only before a certain threshold is reached, and this threshold does not correspond to the minimum language entry requirements. This highlights a systematic disadvantage with which many international students pursue their education.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891700075X?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S136672891700075X</dc:identifier><dc:title>Language and literacy skills of home and international university students: How different are they, and does it matter?</dc:title><prism:startingPage>349</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>365</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S136672891700075X</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891700075X</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-05</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-05</dc:date><dc:creator>TRENKIC, DANIJELA</dc:creator><dc:creator>WARMINGTON, MEESHA</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000299"><title><![CDATA[Code-switching does not predict Executive Function performance in proficient bilingual children: Bilingualism does]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Previous studies of bilingual adults have suggested that bilinguals’ experience with code-switching (CS) contributes to superior executive function (EF) abilities. We tested a highly bilingual developing population in Singapore, a multilingual country where CS occurs pervasively. We obtained CS and EF measures from 43 English–Chinese 8-year-old children (27 females, M = 100 months). We measured spontaneous CS with a novel task and EF in terms of task-switching (Semantic Fluency) and inhibitory control (Stroop task in both languages). Contrary to previous work, CS performance did not significantly predict EF performance in either case. Rather, bilingual language proficiency, i.e., degree of bilingualism (as measured by direct proficiency tests and parents’ estimates of daily language use and exposure of both languages) influenced EF performance. Accordingly, the relationship between CS and EF may be more indirect and non-necessary than previously assumed.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000299?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000299</dc:identifier><dc:title>Code-switching does not predict Executive Function performance in proficient bilingual children: Bilingualism does</dc:title><prism:startingPage>366</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>382</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000299</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000299</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-04-22</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-04-22</dc:date><dc:creator>KANG, CARISSA</dc:creator><dc:creator>LUST, BARBARA</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000044"><title><![CDATA[The predictors of foreign-accentedness in the home language of Polish–English bilingual children]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>We investigated the speech patterns and accentedness of Polish–English bilingual children raised in Great Britain to verify whether their L1 Polish would be perceived as different from that of monolinguals matched for age and socioeconomic status. To this end, Polish-language speech samples of 32 bilinguals and 10 monolinguals (a 3:1 ratio, M<span class='sub'>Age</span> = 5.79) were phonetically analysed by trained phoneticians and rated by 55 Polish raters, who assessed the degree of native accent, intelligibility, acceptability and perceived age. The results show significant differences in the phonetic performance of bilingual and monolingual children – both in terms of atypical speech patterns uncovered in the phonetic analysis and in terms of the holistic accentedness ratings. We also explored the socio-linguistic predictors of accent ratings in bilingual speech and found that the amount of L1 Polish input was the main predictor of accentedness in children's L1 Polish speech, while L2 English input was marginally significant. (149)</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000044?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000044</dc:identifier><dc:title>The predictors of foreign-accentedness in the home language of Polish–English bilingual children</dc:title><prism:startingPage>383</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>400</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000044</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000044</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-03-22</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-03-22</dc:date><dc:creator>WREMBEL, MAGDALENA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARECKA, MARTA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SZEWCZYK, JAKUB</dc:creator><dc:creator>OTWINOWSKA, AGNIESZKA</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000682"><title><![CDATA[Describing bilinguals: A systematic review of labels and descriptions used in the literature between 2005–2015]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>Recent years have seen a surge in research comparing bilinguals to monolinguals, yet synthesizing this literature is complicated by the diversity of language and social backgrounds behind these dichotomous labels. The current study examines the labels and descriptions reported in 186 studies comparing bilinguals and monolinguals published between 2005–2015 in order to understand how bilingualism has been operationalized and to describe the degree to which different facets of bilingual experience are reported. Proficiency and usage were the most frequently reported features (77% and 79%), followed by language history (67%) and the language of schooling (60%). However, less than half of the studies measured proficiency objectively or reported proportional usage, and even less – 30% – described the sociolinguistic context from which the sample was drawn. Given the increase in language contact due to globalization, more transparent and comprehensive reporting of participant characteristics is critical to building our understanding of how bilingualism affects experience.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000682?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728917000682</dc:identifier><dc:title>Describing bilinguals: A systematic review of labels and descriptions used in the literature between 2005–2015</dc:title><prism:startingPage>401</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>415</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728917000682</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728917000682</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2017-12-26</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2017-12-26</dc:date><dc:creator>SURRAIN, SARAH</dc:creator><dc:creator>LUK, GIGI</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000640"><title><![CDATA[A prosodic bias, not an advantage, in bilinguals' interpretation of emotional prosody]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="abstract" data-abstract-type="normal"><p>A bilingual advantage has been found in prosody understanding in pre-school children. To understand this advantage better, we asked 73 children (6-8 years) to identify the emotional valence of spoken words, based on either semantics or emotional prosody (which were either consistent or discrepant with each other). Bilingual experience ranged from no to equal exposure to and use of two languages. Both age and bilingual experience predicted accurate identification of prosody, particularly for trials where the semantics were discrepant with the targeted prosody. Bilingual experience, but not age, predicted a prosodic bias, meaning that participants had more difficulty ignoring the irrelevant discrepant prosody when the task was to identify the semantics of the word. The decline of a semantic bias was predicted by age and bilingual experience together. Our results suggest that previous findings on the bilingual advantage in prosody processing may in fact be driven by a prosodic bias.</p></div>]]></description><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000640?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918000640</dc:identifier><dc:title>A prosodic bias, not an advantage, in bilinguals&apos; interpretation of emotional prosody</dc:title><prism:startingPage>416</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>424</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918000640</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918000640</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2018-06-04</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2018-06-04</dc:date><dc:creator>CHAMPOUX-LARSSON, MARIE-FRANCE</dc:creator><dc:creator>DYLMAN, ALEXANDRA S.</dc:creator></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918001128"><title><![CDATA[BIL volume 22 issue 2 Cover and Front matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918001128?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S1366728918001128</dc:identifier><dc:title>BIL volume 22 issue 2 Cover and Front matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>2</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S1366728918001128</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1366728918001128</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-02-28</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-02-28</dc:date></item><item rdf:about="https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800113X"><title><![CDATA[BIL volume 22 issue 2 Cover and Back matter]]></title><link>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800113X?urlappend=%3Fsource=rss</link><dc:identifier>doi:10.1017/S136672891800113X</dc:identifier><dc:title>BIL volume 22 issue 2 Cover and Back matter</dc:title><prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage><prism:endingPage>2</prism:endingPage><prism:doi>10.1017/S136672891800113X</prism:doi><prism:url>https://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S136672891800113X</prism:url><prism:publicationDate>2019-02-28</prism:publicationDate><prism:volume></prism:volume><prism:number></prism:number><prism:publicationTitle>Bilingualism: Language and Cognition</prism:publicationTitle><dc:date>2019-02-28</dc:date></item></rdf:RDF>